交易所主席简加奇尝试
减低市场对霸菱倒闭的事的恐惧
...denied reports the British banking system is about to collapse.
他向国会发言否认报导  英国银行体系将崩溃
According to him, Barings' failure is a unique situation,...
他说霸菱银行是个别例子
...which he blames on the actions of a rogue trader in Singapore.
是由新加坡的一名股票经纪造成
Estimates of potential losses range from 800 million to over one billion pounds.
估计今次损失达八亿至十亿英镑
股坛狙击手
Look at that!
看看...
Will you fuckin' look at that!
你看清楚
- What, with the black guy? - Yeah.
是个黑人吗？
It's a shame. She looks well spoken for.
真可惜，她看来不错
Never know your luck, though. Eh, mate?
别笑人，小心倒霉
- Think I'll give her the treatment! - No, Steve, no. Don't do that.
我会好好待她                                    不，史提
- No, you're all right. - Don't do that. Steve. Steve!
你不会有事                   史提，不要
Hello, love. I've got something to show ya.
嗨，靓女，我有东西给你看
Are you out of your mind or what? You fuckin' little prick!
你疯了吗？
And I mean little!
别在众人面前出丑
Don't judge a book by its cover, sweetheart.
不要单看外表
- You're out of your league, arsehole. - Calm down.
你太幸运       什么？只是对女士说
Fuck off or you're dead!
滚开，你死定
- I want you out of here, now. - He's really sorry.
立刻出去...                                     他有悔意了
He's pissed. He meant no disrespect. That's the last thing on anybody's mind.
他喝醉，不想惹事的              也不能责骂
Tell him if he doesn't put that thing away,...
叫他把那东西收起，否则
...I'll rip it off and shove it down his fuckin' throat!
怎样？      我会扭着他脖子
Do your flies up, you fuckin' animal. You almost gave me a heart attack.
你这疯狂动物吓坏了我
Just leave it. It's not worth it!
别管他             他不值
He's done it again. I had to pull him off!
再来我便送他到监狱
Fuckin' right laugh!
我不怕的   尽管来
Nick! Nick!
尼克
You all right? Nick!
尼克，没事吧？
It was thanks to Maggie Thatcher opening up the City of London...
谢谢戴卓尔夫人开辟了伦敦市
...that yours truly from Watford came to be working for a posh outfit like Barings.
让我们为霸菱工作
（霸菱银行）
That was me lying on the floor, if you hadn't guessed. Nick Leeson.
这不是真心话   尼克利森，
You've probably heard about me.
应听闻我的名字
Barings was the oldest private bank in the world.
霸菱是全球最悠久银行
They financed the Louisiana Purchase back in eighteen hundred and something.
在1803年   支持美国购入路易斯安纳州
They even had the Queen as a customer!
历史真长久  女皇都是顾客
I was just a humble clerk.
我只是文员
But not for long, I hoped.
希望快晋升
Car crash.
汽车意外
I hit my head on the back of the seat and broke my nose.
我撞到头部和鼻骨折了
Everybody else was all right cos they were wearing their, um... seat belts.
其他人戴安全带，所以没事
Poor chap!
真可怜
Nick, I know you're keen to get out of the back office and onto the trading floor,...
尼克   知道你希望在股市交易所工作
...but in the meantime something else has come up.
但有事发生了
We've got problems in our Jakarta office.
雅加达的公司出事
We need someone to go out there and sort things out.
要派人去处理事务
I thought that someone might be...
或许派尼克利森去？
...Nick Leeson?
Indonesia was one of the new "tiger economies"...
印度尼西亚是远东区
...everyone was getting so excited about.
新亚洲小虎经济国家
"Emerging markets" they were calling them,...
人人都厚望霸菱对新市场
...and Barings was one of the first to see their potential.
很有兴趣
The rewards were high. But so were the risks.
到那里报酬很高   但风险大
One hundred million pounds...
一亿英镑
...in bearer bonds.
As good as cash.
现金
We could pick 'em up, walk out,...
我们立刻起行
...come to some arrangement with laughing boy...
无后顾之忧
Customers refuse to pay for them.
顾客不愿付钱
They say what's on them doesn't match the original deal.
说协议价钱  与原本有别
The real reason: the market goes down, they don't want any more.
原因是市场下跌  他们不想负责
It's a mess.
很难搞
You're absolutely 100 per cent right, Susi. It's one hell of a fuckin' mess.
苏慈，你说得对  真难搞
周日早上十时 飞机到二十哩
It was my job to sort out the certificates...
我工作是整理证明文件
...so customers wouldn't have any more excuses not to pay.
顾客无可抵赖
Until then, Barings had this bloody great hole in their balance sheet.
令霸菱免受损失
It was boring work, but I knew if I made a success of it...
这工作很闷，但若成功...
...then I could write my own ticket.
便成真正经纪
All the certificates are in the right denomination.
所有证明文件没有错
I've sorted out all the documentation. That's all in order now, so...
我把所有文件顺序好
...all I need from you...
只需签发支票
...is a cheque!
Hello. I'm Lisa.
我是丽莎
I'm, um... Nick Leeson. Can I help you?
我是尼克利森   有何贵干
Barings sent me to help with the settlements.
霸菱派来协助你
Didn't they tell you?
没告诉你？
Oh, of course! I've been on at them for so long I never thought they'd get round to it.
当然有           是很久的事，以为他们忘了
What do we do with that lot? Build a bonfire?
那么干什么？开营火会？
I'd never even heard of Barings before I started working for 'em.
在霸菱工作前我没听过它的名
It's not like there's a Barings in Watford.
和华福的霸菱不同
You're a hero in London. They think the sun shines out of your arse.
你在伦敦成为英雄  他们认为你干得很好
Really? I was beginning to feel like one of those Japanese soldiers.
真的？ 感到自己像日本武士
Still stuck out in the jungle 20 years after the war!
二十年后从森林到现实
What's it like here? They tell me it's not safe at night.
这里是怎样？晚间外出很危险
Bollocks. The locals are great.
夸大，这城市很有活力
And it's not full of pompous ex-colonials thinking they were born to rule the world.
好处是不会有自大的英国人  以为这里由他们管治
That's what I love about Asia.
所以我爱亚洲
Anyone can make it. Doesn't matter which school you went to.
无论是否出自名校都有机会
When they told me I was going to Jakarta I had to look it up on the map.
当派到雅加达时   我要在地图找它呢！
As a matter of fact, so did I.
我也是
I really want to be a trader.
我想当股票经纪
If Barings don't let me on the floor after this, I'm off.
若霸菱不让我当经纪便离开
- Not gonna be bloody clerking all my life. - Ooh! Ambitious, aren't we?
不想一生当文员                       我们有野心，对吗？
- Is that bad? - It's great.
不好吗？          真好
I just want to get on in life.
我想干一番事业
I like to enjoy myself, don't get me wrong. Work hard, play hard.
我享受人生尽情工作和玩乐
Well, I think this is me.
我的房间
Well, night, Nick. That was fun.
尼克，晚安          很愉快
Yeah, it was, wasn't it?
对
- OK. Night-night! - See you tomorrow, then.
好了，晚安               明天见
Lisa was a stunner all right.
丽莎真美
Love at first sight.
一见钟情
Together we made short work of the rest of those bonds.
我们一起很有感觉
Soon we cleared up most of Barings' losses and it was time to go home.
我们做完霸菱的呆坏帐准备回家
See you later, Lisa.
丽莎，再见
Bye.
再见
I think you'll agree that in Nick Lisa has met her prince.
尼克是丽莎心目中的王子
Hear! Hear!
注意了
Join me in wishing them well in their new life in Singapore,...
恭祝他们在新加坡的新生活
...where Nick is to be general manager of the trading floor. Whatever that means.
尼克会是股票交易部经理
It impressed the hell out of me, but...
他表现很出色
And, um...
尼克
To you, Nick, I'm entrusting the most precious of gifts.
我们送你珍贵的礼物
I know you're gonna look after her and cherish her...
要好好待她爱护她
...and all those other things. And if you don't,...
比其他重要      否则
...I'll break your bloody legs, all right?
打断你双腿
He means it!
他认真的
I love you so much, Lisa Leeson.
丽莎利森，我爱你
I love you too, Nick.
尼克，我也爱你
As a reward for Jakarta I'd been given the far more important market of Singapore,...
由于在雅加达很成功         所以派我到新加坡       更重要市场
...with a brief to set up my own trading operation.
在这设立运作架构
I was definitely on my way.
要全力以赴
- And the kitchen... - This is your department, darling.
厨房呢              这是新居
Since when? Cheeky!
何时入住？
And the bedroom...
还有睡房
Yes
对
- If you need anything, call me. - Right, thanks.
若有需要，可找我          谢谢你
- Have a nice day. - Thanks. Bye.
祝你愉快         谢谢，再见
Goodbye.
再见
Not bad for a chancer from Watford, eh?
算不错吧
Well, um... I think we should test out that mattress, big boy.
先试试睡床是否舒服
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah!
要吗？    要
I can't see any problem in you handling both sides of the operation.
目前你在处理业务上并无犯错
- At least until volumes increase. - Right.
并数额大增             对
You shouldn't need more than two on the trading floor.
你不需超过两个助手
A couple more in the back office.
而要多个文职处理转帐
No need to pay top dollar.
无须高薪
Get them young, get them hungry and train them up.
只要年轻肯学习
- I'm a bottom line kind of guy, Nick. - Absolutely. That's my philosophy.
尼克，简单好了                                  当然，这也是经营哲学
I took him at his word. My team were young, hungry...
如他说，我的队员很年轻
...and they didn't have a clue.
他们好学，但对股市没经验
A futures contract allows you to buy or sell a specified amount of a commodity...
期指合约是一份    买卖合约
...at a specified price at a future date.
在指定日期的指定价格
Right. Um...
对
It's like, if I agree to sell you this cup of cappuccino, which I don't yet own,...
若我同意把咖啡卖给你
...at 45 cents a month from now...
我在一个月后以四十五仙卖给你
If I can buy the cappuccino at, say, 43 cents, I make a profit.
到时我花四十三仙买到，便赚钱
If the price goes the other way I have to pay more, and I lose.
若价钱上升要多花钱，便是亏损
It's timing - buying and selling at the right moment.
关键就是买卖的时间
Sometimes espresso might be the best deal, or salt, or pepper.
有时咖啡最赚钱是盐或胡椒
So, we're running a supermarket?
就像经营超级市场
We're not buying and selling anything real.
其实没有进行真正买卖
It's just numbers - contracts based on the value of the Nikkei,...
只是数字游戏           游戏是依照日经股票市场
...the Tokyo stock market.
游戏是依照日经股票市场
- Er, we do this for the bank? - No, no, for the customers.
这是为银行做？                 --不，是为顾客
We are not allowed to trade on behalf of the bank.
我们不准代表银行炒卖
Be sure you remember that, all right?
要紧记这点
Other dealers wear red jackets. All same. Red is lucky Chinese colour.
交易员全都穿着红褛    红色是中国人的幸运颜色
Well, we want to stand out. We're a new operation. We need to be noticed.
对，所以我们要特别点    新的运作要被人注目
May be bad luck. Different colour.
不同的颜色会带来不幸
Bollocks. We make our own luck.
别傻，我们有彩数
Nick's right. We're cool dudes, man. Whoo!
尼克说得对，我们很帅
Fernando. Anything happening in Tokyo?
法兰度，东京有什么发生吗？
Nothin'. How's SIMEX?
没什么，新加坡市场呢？
Same here. No one's playin'.
一样，成交量只有五百九十
590, and trading small.
600, and thin too.
不足六百
580 here. There's a seller who wants to trade in size. Shall I low-tick him?
五百八十，有买家想大手入市    要给低价吗？
Yeah. Flush him out.
好，让他买入呢
- Squeeze the sucker. - How many?
把坏人赶走              --多少？
200.
二百
Buy them... now.
现在买入
- Buy 'em! - Filled!
买入            --补仓
We paid 580 for 200.
你以五百八十元买入二百手
Way to go, Nick! I sold at 590.
尼克，我刚以五百九十沽货
Fuck a duck! Just made 2,000 quid.
该死，刚赚到二千英镑
Yes!
对
They were a good bunch and they were keen to learn.
他们很好学  股票经纪各施各法
It looked like a madhouse with all the traders waving and shouting,...
就像马场一样刺激
...but it all made sense once you got the hang of it.
置身其中更难忘    我干了什么？
There were hiccups, but that's normal in any operation,...
市场有起有跌     这是很正常
...especially a new one like ours.
对新人而言
The important thing was we were picking up the business...
最重要令生意上升
...and the future looked rosy.
未来充满憧憬
Nick, what's the difference between initial margin and variation margin?
尼克   单一I展和综合I展有何分别
Initial margin's a down payment on each futures contract that we trade.
单一I展是只付期指合约首期
We don't pay in full until a contract matures.
在合约期满前也不需付全数
But in the meantime the value of each contract may go up or down.
但每份合约都会各别升跌
So SIMEX calculate our positions on a daily basis.
新加坡交易所每日计我们的交易
They'll ask for more money if the market goes against us. That's variation margin.
当市场与投资有分差便要补仓   这叫综合I展
Got it. I think!
我明白了
We need to open an errors account. We've had a few mistakes.
我们要开一个记错户口  我们有点错，虽没什么，但...
I need somewhere to put them till I can write them out.
我把帐目转到那里直至填补错误
Sure. What number shall I give it?
好的，我们要什么户口号码？
- Well, what's your lucky number? - Eight. It is a very lucky Chinese number.
你的幸运号码？               --八号，中国人喜欢八号
And how many numbers do we need?
要多少个号码
Five.
五个
Then let's give it all the luck it can handle. Call it the 88888 account.
就起个幸运号码  叫88888户口吧
And now it gives me great pleasure to welcome the chairman of Barings Bank,...
我很荣幸为你介绍   霸菱主席
...Peter Baring.
彼得霸菱
We may be the oldest merchant bank in the world,...
我们是全球最悠久的银行之一
...but that's no excuse for not keeping up with the times.
但并不代表我们过时
When I became chairman,...
当我上任主席一职后
...I realised we couldn't go on running Barings like a gentlemen's club.
我发现不可把它当成俱乐部
We had to look beyond our traditional recruiting grounds,...
我们要打破  传统管治方法...
...the old school tie,...
传统学校领带
...to seek out a new and hungrier breed.
寻求新的管理方式
We're beginning to see the fruits of those efforts, and I have to say,...
我们开始看到成效      利润...
...the recovery in profitability, since the reorganisation, has been... amazing.
更大幅回升
To be frank, I've discovered it's not actually terribly difficult...
坦白说... 在证券业务中赚取利润并不困难
...to make money in the securities business!
在证券业务中赚取利润并不困难
Filled.
补仓
Yeah, you paid 50 for 20.
对，以五十元买二十手
Come in.
进来
Simon, er... I've got a slight problem.
辛逊，我出了一点问题
One of the girls sold 20 contracts for Fuji Bank instead of buying.
有一女职员为富士银行  买入二十手，却误沽货了
I can't do anything about it till Monday.
我要周一才修补这问题
What's the damage?
损失多少
20,000 at the close.
收市时达二万
Sack the cow. She'll never work on SIMEX again.
开除她   她不可再工作
That's a bit hard, isn't it?
太不近人情吧！
Look, you handle it.
自己处理吧
Have a word with London, but make sure you make that client good.
向伦敦汇报，要令客户满意
All right.
好吧
Hey! Have a beer, shithead!
喝杯酒吧
Cheers.
干杯
Hi, darling.
嗨，老公
Anyone seen Kim?
看到金吗
She was here a minute ago.
她之前还在...
Kim...
金
Nick, Nick...
尼克
I'm really sorry. I got so confused.
尼克，对不起
- Everybody was shouting all at once. - That's the job.
当各人都在大喊，太混乱了
That's what it's all about, keeping a cool head.
这份工作就是要保持冷静
I'm so sorry! I'll pay you back the money.
对不起，我会赔钱给你
Sure, Kim. Four years' salary? And if the market moves it could be even worse.
金，那是你四年的薪酬    若市场再有变动情况更糟
Come on, come on.
来
Come on, everyone makes mistakes.
每个人都会犯错
Look, with a bit of luck I can trade out of it on Monday, all right?
若幸运，周一定会渡过难关
Nick, I've been waiting for you while everyone else is having a good time.
尼克，我一直在等你
- I'm going home now. - Kim!
我要回家了              --金
Kim...!
金
- Everything all right? - Never better.
顺利吗？               --很顺利
Why don't you let me come in and help? I can't sit around all day doing nothing.
让我到公司帮你，我不想游手好闲
It's not a problem, Lisa.
丽莎，不是这问题
I can handle it.
我处理得来
Fernando, how are March futures looking?
法兰度，三月的数目怎样？
- I need 20 contracts at Friday's price. - You won't get Friday's price!
我暂时没有周五价格
I should have closed off the position and taken the loss.
我应该周一开始便平仓
Instead, I waited for the market to change.
总比等市场变动好
It changed all right, but not the way I wanted.
它的确变动了，但不是如我所愿
Now I was stuck with a bigger loss than I could own up to. And it was all my fault.
我损失更多金钱   这是我的错
Nick! I hear your girl handed in her notice.
尼克，听闻你的下属金辞职了
Never came back. She couldn't stand the pace.
对，她受不了这些压力
So much for loyalty!
够仗义
- Did you make the client good? - Of course. Made a small profit, actually.
你的顾客怎么了          --还好，有一点点进帐
Good man.
那很好
This one's for the five eights account.
这是属于88888户口
I bought the missing contracts.
我找到了那些合约
60,000?
合共六万英镑吗
- Shh! - It was only 20 before.
之前只是二万英镑
And the market went the wrong way. I had to cut the loss.
当市场变坏时我便立刻沽货
What did Simon Jones say?
辛森钟斯说什么
Are you serious? He'd shut us down if he knew.
你认真的吗   若他知真相定会辞退我们
It'll be all right so long as we balance the books by the end of the month.
只要在月底能收支平衡便没问题
- How? - We trade on our own account...
怎可能    --我们用自己的户口进行买卖
...until we wipe out the losses, then we use money from the client account...
直至填补损失为止    我们用顾客的钱
...and pay it back with next month's profits.
利用下个月的利润填补给客户
You mean, gamble?
你要作赌注吗
Relax, Bonnie. That's all the market is.
放心，邦妮    股市就如赌场一样
One giant casino!
浩大之极
George!
佐治
I was counting on nobody looking at the books until the end of each month.
我希望无人会在月结前翻查帐目
As long as the five eights account had a nil balance on the last day of the month,...
只要88888户口在每月最后一天   显示出没有盈余
...no one would suspect that anything was wrong.
便不会惹人怀疑
But instead of winning back the position we made more losses,...
不但没有反转劣势反而越赌越输
...and I had to borrow more money from the client account to hide them.
我要从客户的户口   借钱来隐瞒真相
Fuckin' hell, George, what are you playing at? Get fuckin' out!
佐治，你在玩什么？滚
Get fuckin' out! Now!
立刻给我滚
What the hell are you playing at? Out! Get out!
你在玩什么？滚        好了
Fuckin' hell!
该死的
- Agh. - God, you're tense. Stiff as a board.
你太紧张了
If you only knew! All cos those bastards won't let me hire proper staff.
你不明白    他们不让我聘用合适的员工
- I thought it was going so well. - It is. It's going brilliant.
我还以为一切顺利          --不错
I just spend most of my life covering everybody else's arse.
我只是忙于收拾别人的残局
Well, why don't you let me help with the back office?
不如让我到公司帮你吧
- I'm bored being a lady of leisure. - No.
我平时在家中呆着呢
Why not? It's ridiculous, you having to handle trading and settlements.
尼克，为何？ 文职事业不是由你负担
You'll have a nervous breakdown.
你快要精神崩溃了
I don't want you interfering. I can handle it.
因为我不想你介入我可以处理的
All right, keep your pants on! No one's saying you can't.
好吧，那么你别发怒  你一定做得到
I'm not going back to being a bloody clerk. I'd rather be a plasterer.
我不回去当文员   我宁愿当抹灰匠
My mum always used to say I could be anything I wanted,...
我妈妈常说  只要有恒心，铁柱磨成针
...so long as I took my chances - and worked like a dog.
只要肯努力
Well, you have. You've worked really hard and it paid off.
你已经很努力了，而且还得回报
She'd have been so proud of you.
她一定为你而自豪
Do you really think so?
真的吗
Yeah.
当然
I know I am!
对
That was the worst part - Lisa thinking I was this brilliant success.
最惨的是丽莎以为我是天才
If she only knew what a fuck-up I really was!
她并不知道我其实很不济
When I wanted the market to go up, it went down.
当我想股市上升时它便下跌
If I wanted it to go down, it went up.
我想它下跌它却又上升
It was hard not to take it personally.
这真难缠
Nick?
尼克？
Nick! I just worked out the balance in the eights account.
我刚计算了88888的收支平衡
- The losses are over $10 million! - Keep your fuckin' voice down!
我们损失了超过一千万元        --邦妮，别这么大声
Look, there's no need to panic.
也不用那么慌张
There's not enough in the client account to make margin payments, Nick.
客户的帐户不够钱填补I展欠款
Right.
没错
I need dollars. I need dollars to cover the initial margin payment!
我需要钱填补最初的I展欠款
I can get dollars from London to cover all the client positions for the futures I buy!
我叫伦敦汇钱给我填补这些损失
Nothing unusual about that. But I'm gonna need yen.
这样也不是罕见       但我需要日圆
Gonna need yen to cover the daily variation columns!
以便在月底前
Which'll leave a yen deficit by the end of the month.
填补所损失的日圆
Unless... unless I sell options.
除非... 我沽售期权来换取日圆佣金
That'll generate commission in yen.
我沽售期权来换取日圆佣金
And return the balance sheet on the five eights account to zero!
将88888户口维持零进帐
As long as London kept sending out money to finance the client positions,...
只要我能说服伦敦总公司汇钱
...I'd have enough cash to stay on top of the margin payments.
给我填补损失
It was like robbing Peter to pay Paul,...
这只是亡羊补牢
...but hopefully I'd end up making enough to pay Peter back before he found out.
但我希望赚到足够的金钱 给我填补损失
Meanwhile I had to generate more and more business to justify my cash calls,...
其间  我要找更多生意来证明
...and for that I needed customers.
我是为顾客利益要求现金资助
The bigger the better.
越多越好
Mm-hm. Oui.
好
Mr Leeson.
利森先生...
- I'm Pierre Beaumarchais. - Nice to meet you.
我是彼亚波马斯          --很高兴认识你
I work for the Geneva Banking Trust, based in the Bahamas.
我以巴哈马为基地的日内瓦银行工作
I was speaking with Ang Swee Tian, president of SIMEX.
我刚兴新加坡交易市所总裁  安维田谈话
He's impressed by the amount of business you've been generating.
因你为他赚取的生意额感满意
- There's a lot of opportunities here. - Oh, yes.
外边有很多机会           --就是
I do a lot of business on SIMEX.
我在新加坡市场也参与很多交易
With the exception of George Soros,...
除了佐治罗索斯
...I probably trade in the Nikkei more than anyone.
我在日经市场的投资比任何人多
Sometimes over 5,000 contracts in a day.
一日通常高达五千张合约
That is a lot. The whole market only does about 20.
整个市场的成交量只有二十左右
Could Barings handle that amount of business?
霸菱可以处理这么大的生意吗
You bet we could!
当然可以
Beaumarchais was the answer to my prayers.
波马斯是我的救星
I'd be able to siphon off enough commission...
我利用当中所得的佣金
...to square the eights account once and for all.
一次过填补88888户口的损失
- Hello? - Pierre Beaumarchais.
彼亚波马斯
I want to buy 4,000 June contracts.
我想买四千张六月份的合约
I've... got a price of 350, but this'll move it.
目前的价格是三百五十  但股价不断变动
Try not to pay more than 400.
升幅别超过四百元
We gotta get them cheap. Beaumarchais is a big player.
我们低水入货  波马斯是大玩家
If we pull this off, we get a shitload of business.
若我们讨得他欢心便不愁没生意
- What's liquidity like? - Tight as a flea's arse.
流动资产如何          --只有很少
We'll get away with 500, then the price will move up.
我们在五百点沽货 之后股市上升
OK. But then we'll make the other traders think we're sellers.
要令其他交易家以为我们要沽货
And when the price drops... buy! All right?
到股价下跌时再买入
OK.
好的
Sell 250!
二百五十点沽货
Sell 250! Sell 250!
Sell 240!
二百五十点沽货
Sell 240! Sell 240!
二百四十点沽货
Sell 200! Sell 200!
二百点沽货
- Buy 500 contracts! - Sell 200!
买五百手         --二百点沽货
Buy? Buy?
要买吗
Buy at 200! Buy at 200! Buy at 210!
在二百点买入
Buy at 210! Buy at 220!
在二百一十点买入
Buy at 220! Buy at 230!
在二百二点买入
Buy at 240!
在二百一十点买入
Buy at 240! Buy at 240!
Filled!
弄好
Nobody saw us coming! We swooped on the first 1500 like a Stealth bomber!
没人估计到我们的策略       我们转眼赚了一百五十万
4,000 contracts!
四千手
Balls of steel, Fat Boy. Balls of fuckin' steel!
肥仔，快点买
At last my luck had changed. Suddenly I couldn't stop making money.
我终于行运了  我突然停不了赚大钱
I was long in the Nikkei - that meant gambling on it going up - and up it went.
对准日经平均指数的走势    在炒股生意上取得优势  上落尽在我掌握之中
Up and up and up.
股市继续上升
That's very good! Very good.
尼克，干得好
Serves you right, Lisa!
加班
If it went all the way up to 19,000, I stood to make a killing on the options I'd sold.
若指数继续上升至一万九千点  我沽售所有期权后一定赚大钱
Come on, come on! Come on, baby, you can do it. Come on.
来吧...快
- Yes! - Yes!
好
Bonnie, we're on a fuckin' roll!
邦妮，我们成功了
Yes!
是的
Do you think we'll do it?
我还以为功亏一篑
It's amazing! You've made back all the losses.
神奇，你填补了超过...
- Over $10 million. - What did I tell you? Oh, ye of little faith!
一千万元的损失           --我说过要有信心
You keep doubling up, and sooner or later...
你继续加倍入货很快我们便赚钱
...you're bound to win.
The Nikkei has closed up for the third day in a row,...
日经平均指数连续第三日停市
...and the rally shows little sign of running out of steam.
Analysts are predicting additional gains in the days ahead.
但没迹象显示会炒风过热...
- Happy? - Yeah. Are you?
开心吗             你呢？
Never better.
从未如此开心过
I have been sailing a bit close to the wind. I didn't want to worry you with it.
最初时损失了一点   但我不想令你担心
- What do you mean? - No, it's all right.
你说什么    没什么
The market turned round and a whole load of my positions came good.
市场改变，让我填补了损失
I made it all back.
What are you on about, Nick?
你怎么了
Don't get your knickers in a twist, but we made mistakes and ran up some losses.
别担心，我只是犯了一点错
I went out on a limb to get back the position.
所以我要赌一赌把钱赚回来
How big were the losses?
你损失多少
- It's about a million. - A million quid?!
大约一百万                      一百万英镑？
For God's sake, Nick!
尼克，你太过分
No, it's all right. It paid off. I squared it up.
没事了，已经赚回来
I had to do it to protect the guys.
我要保护我的下属
Promise me that you'll never do that again.
答应我不要再这样干
- It's not worth it, Nick. - I promise.
你不值得这样做    我答应你
You will give me a heart attack.
你快把我吓得心脏病发
- Merry Christmas. - Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Fuck off!
该死
I really meant it. I was the number one trader, and as the new year came in...
我认真的   我是城中最成功交易员
...I was determined to kick my addiction to the eights account.
踏入新年，我决要    好好利用88888户口
What will the market do? Long-term?
你认为应长线    投资吗？
No one thinks long-term, they think nanoseconds!
你说笑吧，没人会考虑长线投资
- Long-term's tomorrow morning. - Tomorrow, then.
长线就是明天    就依你所说的
- That would be telling. - Leeson speaks, the market moves!
一言为定    利森的举动足以令市场变动
You said it, mate.
一言为定
Pierre.
彼亚
I want to sell the 220 call options and buy the 200 calls in December.
我要沽二百二十手看涨期权  在十二月买入二百手涨期权
I've got an offer of .138 for size.
你会有一点三八巴仙的佣金
Can you do better?
你做得到吗
I'll get back to you.
我再联络你
Quick as you can, Nick. I have to move fast.
尼克，我们要速战速决
What the hell is he on about, .138 for size?
什么？谁人会出这个价钱
The market in 220 calls is down. He wants to cut his losses.
沽二百二十手会亏蚀的   我们要为客人止蚀
- Yeah, but why .138? - It's a ratio.
为何出这价钱？         他们以百分率计算
The 200 calls are trading at 1,400.
以二百手换一千四百手
Divide 200 by 1,400, you get .143.
你便可以获得  一点四三巴仙的佣金
All right. But not .138.
但不是一点三八巴仙的佣金
Unless someone's offered him a discount. Probably Societe Generale.
除非有人给他折扣  彼亚是我们主要的客户
We can't let those wankers get our biggest client.
不能损失这个客人
- What are you gonna do? - Just have to leg it.
你打算怎样             我们一定要帮他
Buy the contracts from Pierre and sell them when the market rises?
你是说向彼亚买入那期股票             然后趁高沽货
I thought we were not supposed to trade for the bank.
我们不应为银行作买卖
Pierre? I can do it. What's the exact size?
彼亚，我可帮你，有多少期货
6,500? All right, leave it with me. No problem.
六千五百？等我来处理
What if the market doesn't rise, uh? What if it falls?
若股市下跌不上升那怎办
I've gambled and won before. I can gamble and win again.
我曾赌博胜了，一定可以再赢
Balls of steel, me old mateys, and you'd better believe it.
我是神奇小子，你要信我
Bonnie, I need you to reopen the eights account.
邦妮        你再为我开启88888户口
We got caned on Beaumarchais' contracts.
我们被那些波马斯的股票害死
Now the bastard's gone back to Societe Generale.
那些混旦找中央股票行帮他们
Fax Brenda Granger in London. Ask her for funds to cover the margin payments.
你传真给佩达   叫她多点资金以应付I展款项
Tell her it's for client positions.
说是为了她的客户
Hello?
你好
It's Simon. Can you come into my office?
尼克，我是辛逊  到我办公室，
Right away.
有事找你
Christ, I'd been rumbled! The only surprise was it'd taken so long.
一定是出事   终于被揭发
What was I gonna tell Lisa? She'd bloody murder me.
我怎告诉丽莎？她定会宰了我
Come in.
进来
Congratulations, Nick.
尼克，恭喜你
The '93 bonuses are in, and you're down for 135 grand.
九三年的花红发放了          你有一三五万
135? That's fantastic!
一三五？真不错
Your little operation generated profits of over 10 million last year. You're a star!
去年为公司赚了超过一千万英镑   你是我们的明星
In fact, your figures are so high they're going to check up on you.
因为你赚了巨额数目   所以他们要核数
Check up on me?
查核我的帐目？
They're sending Ash Lewis out for the audit.
他们派艾斯路易斯来
Don't worry. It's purely routine.
别担心，只是例行工作
Ash Lewis?
艾斯路易斯？
She's meant to be a right ball-breaker, isn't she?
男人见到她便怕
That's our booth.
那是我们展览摊位
Filled! You paid 250.
全都满了，你付二百五十
Hi, Nick.
尼克
Ron Baker and Ash Lewis.
这是朗伯嘉，他是艾斯路易斯
Ron is head of Derivatives Trading in London.
朗是负责伦敦市场的主管
Which I guess makes me your boss, Nick.
我便是你的上司
- How do you, Mr Leeson? - Very well, thank you.
很高兴认识你    利森先生，你好吗   很好，谢谢
OK Let's see the action!
我们开始工作
Henry!
亨利
Who's doing all the business? We're the biggest, right?
谁负责这主意？我们最大的
We do a lot of arbitrage, so we do have a high volume.
我们为客人处理套利活动   所以交易量很大
We signal orders in to George in the pit - this is Henry -
我们把所有交易通知佐治
...and at the end of the day the girls in the office
这是亨利，每天收市后
they log all the deals on to the computer.
公司女同事便用电脑纪录交易
You manage the trading floor and the settlements office, is that right?
你是交易场内的经理，对吗
Yes, yes.
亨利，你在一百的位置加了记号
That's a little unusual. Whatever happened to checks and balances?
这是比较罕见的  谁负责审查收支平衡
- That's something we need to talk about. - I'll be here for three weeks.
这方面我们要详细汇报             我会留在这里三周
This is going to be a thoroughly comprehensive audit. No stone unturned.
今次是详尽的审核            每一项都会审核
Absolutely. Anything I can do to help, any stone needs turning, let me know.
当然，我会尽力提供协助          有什么发现便告诉我
Are we filled? Good man, Henry.
我们完成了吗？亨利
Nice to see you, Simon.
辛逊，很高兴见到你
Dad's seen this flat in Blackheath.
爸爸认为值得投资在黑希
Needs a bit of work, but him and my granddad can fix it up.
那房屋需要修葺         但爸和祖父可负责
Think of it like an insurance policy in case you get sacked,...
如被开除，可当是一项保险
...have to go back to England and work as a plasterer!
回英国你可当抹灰工人
What's up with you, misery-guts?
怎么了？
What would you do, Lise ? What would you do if I did get the elbow?
丽莎，你干什么            若我失业你干什么
You've just been given a ruddy great big bonus.
你刚收到丰厚的花红
But what if it all went wrong? What if I'm not as clever as everyone thinks?
若突然出现问题？         我不是别人所想的聪明
Oh, of course you are!
你当然是
Anyway, it's you I love. I don't give a toss about the money.
我爱不是你的钱财
If it was up to me we'd jack it all in now, go back to England and start a family.
希望立刻回英国建立我们的家庭
You're doing brilliantly, Nick.
尼克，你很聪明
You're a bloody star.
你真聪明
- Nick! - Fuck!
尼克？    该死
Simon!
辛逊
- You're looking disgustingly chirpy. - Haven't you heard? Panic over.
什么事？你神不守舍             你听到吗？
- Ash has been called back to London. - You're kidding. Why?
艾灰被召回伦敦              说笑吧？为何？
Office politics. Some turf battle between Futures and Securities.
办公室政治        霸菱期货和霸菱证券政治斗争
- And what about the audit? - They'll send Mark Taylor and Chris Carr.
核数的事怎样了                    他们派马克泰和基斯卡来
Compared to Ash they're a couple of pussies.
他们没艾灰那样精明
Pity. I was rather looking forward to seeing the dreaded Ash Lewis in action!
真可惜          我想看看艾灰的结局
Yes!
是吗
No, I'm just leaving now.
不，我要走了
I'm gonna jump in the shower. If you get home first, put the oven on.
我去洗澡           若你先回家开动h炉
- All right, sweetheart. I'll see you then. - Bye, darling.
好吧，待会见                 再见
- Get in, you bastard! - What the fuck is that?
该死的进来    这是什么
Sex on wheels. It's a Porsche, moron! Get in!
最美的保时捷，笨旦，上车吧
I'll tell you what it is.
让我告诉你，这辆车很恶心
It's disgustin'.
I'll tell you what it is. It's a great big hard-on!
让我告诉你，它令我兴奋
Got to think of something to do with my bonus.
我要好好享受我的花红
You keep your eyes on the road, you flash git!
小心驾驶
- It's a fuckin' one-way street, George. - Whoops!
佐治，你该死的
Goodness, gracious, great balls of steel!
- Whoo! - Fuckin' George!
佐治，你该死的
Shit! There's that Reuters journalist.
该死，是路透社的记者
Nick! Nick!
尼克...
He's been bugging me for weeks for an interview.
他要求和我做访问
- Hey, Nick! - All right, mate?
尼克    你好吗
Nick, my man. What'll you have?
尼克，最近好吗
Oh, a beer, please. You know George Seow, one of my dealers?
给我啤酒         你认识我经纪佐治吗
This is Danny from Intercontinental Trading.
这位是越州交易所的丹尼
- Just been sent from the London office. - Nice to meet you. Heard a lot about you.
刚由伦敦调职到这里                     丹尼，很高兴认识你  我也是，久仰大名
I hear Barings have almost cornered the market here, thanks to you.
我听闻霸菱声名大噪全归功于你
The rumours have been greatly exaggerated.
这些谣传太夸张了
Don't be so modest.
别谦虚了
He's king of the exchange! Barings got an award for all the business he's generated.
你知道他们怎样叫他   交易之王  新加坡市场刚颁发奖项给他   表扬他的成就
- Do you want a beer? - I'd love a beer.
你要啤酒    我要
Watch the Drambuie settle.
一定令你头昏脑涨
And it's called depth charge.
It's guaranteed to blow your fuckin' head off.
一定令你头昏脑涨
NO
不要...
Are you ready?
你准备好吗
Let's do it. Let's have it.
行动吧
One!
好了    来吧
And two!
一...二...三
And three!
现在
- Bottoms up! - Bottoms up!
干杯    干杯
Hey! Pretty women! What are you waiting for?
美女，你在等什么？
Come on!
来吧
- Come on! - Tough shit, George.
佐治，该死
Your charm's just not working tonight.
你的魅力今晚不凑效
Stuck-up bitches!
该死的婆娘
- I bet they're Singapore air hostesses. - Flight lieutenants, if you don't mind!
我猜她们是新加坡航空的空姐            应该是空中服务员
Chocks away!
废话
Flight lieutenants...!
空中服务员
Help 'em to decide if they wanna come in or if they don't wanna come in.
你去帮她们决定来还是不来
Let's give 'em a hand and moon 'em!
助她们一臂之力
That should help 'em decide. Come on, don't be shy!
帮她们作决定             别害羞
Your mother wasn't!
你妈妈不会
I love this man.
我爱上这男人
- On three? - It worked before.
再来三声    都试过了
It could work again. One...
今次一定行...一
Two! Three!
一...二...三
Bottoms up!
干杯
That is disgusting!
恶心
What'll it be, you old bastard?
老鬼，你喝什么？
Absolutely brilliant, Nick! Drinks are on me.
尼克，你很聪明，我请客
Enough depth charges to sink a battleship!
我的智慧可令敌人全军覆没
- Fuck, what time is it? - I don't know.
现在什么时候？          不知道
Got to phone Lisa.
我要致电丽莎
对，致电给她    去找她
Oh, you've got to be jokin'!
你说笑吧
No laughing matter.
不是
Outraging a lady's modesty... very serious crime in Singapore.
在新加坡侮辱女性是严重的罪行
News of my disgrace reached London. At the highest level.
我的罪行连伦敦总公司也知道
It's slightly embarrassing, but one of our traders got drunk...
情况有点尴尬
...and pulled a moon.
我们的人在新加坡后闹事
What did you say?
你说什么
He exposed his bottom.
他露体...
- Why? - Playing silly buggers, I expect.
为什么            我猜他们在输赌
Unfortunately, the law over there takes rather a dim view.
当地政府视这行为为严重重行
Maybe we should sack him.
应辞退他吗
Sacking him would be... awkward, to say the least.
这样做太惹人注目了
He generates a significant amount of our profits in Southeast Asia.
他为我们在东南亚分区赚大钱
I, er... ought to mention we're getting stick from the Bank of England...
他为我们的英国银行赚大钱
...about our funding over there.
Technically we're in breach of regulations on the ratio of lending to capital.
技术上违反政府条例        动用超出规定的资本比率
Would you like me to have a quiet word in their ear?
你想我和他们私下谈谈吗
Oh, we're not quite there yet.
还不是时候
When I spoke to Andy Dixon at the Bank, he said the matter was...
银行那方面的安迪说
..."buried reasonably deep in his in-tray".
他想把这件事低调处理
Just flagging a concern.
别让人想起这件事来
Quite right. It's something we should keep an eye on.
但要继续留意事态发展
Well... is that it? Any other business?
还有其他事吗
Well, what about this chap Leeson? He of the exhibitionist tendencies.
这个利森怎么办？他是露体狂
I suppose it's something we should leave to the Singapore authorities.
这些事应由当地政府处理
I have to say... I'm inclined to agree.
我同意
So, it was the profits that saved me.
事实上那些利润救了我一命
If they only knew!
Nick!
尼克，
That guy from Reuters again. The second time today.
又是那个路透社记者     他第二次致电来找你
Tell him I've...
告诉他...
Oh, fuck it! Gimme the phone.
把电话给我
Print me up a balance on the eights account.
为我编88888户口结算单
Hi, Loy.
莱，情况如何？
Nick! You're a hard man to pin down.
尼克，找你很难
You know how it is. What can I do you for?
你该明白，有何贵干
- Quite a position you've been buying. - We're happy.
你近来活跃买卖
I don't know how the client wants to play it.
我们很成功  不知顾客喜欢如何玩
Who is this mystery client, Nick? He must have rather large balls.
尼克，那神秘客户是谁？ 他一定有钱    对不起
I'm sorry, mate. Client confidentiality and all that.
你明白这是客户的私隐
Is it Pierre Beaumarchais?
他是彼亚巴查吗
Sorry, Loy, I... gotta go. I'll speak to you later.
对不起，莱，我要挂线
Speak to you some other time.
再联络
Jesus Christ, Bonnie. It's 7.78 billion yen!
邦妮  七十七亿八十万日圆
- Do you want the dollar amount? It's... - Yeah, yeah, $77.8 million.
你要知道美金是多少吗？     一美元对一百日圆 总数七千七百万美元
Book me the following notional trade.
为我纪录这项交易
Selling 1,000 December 21,500 put options at a price of... 7778.
十二月卖出二万一千五百手 令期权的价位升至七七七八
Then print me a new report after that entry so it shows 7.78 billion yen...
然后把交易编给我 交易帐单上会显示
- ... as if it was owing to us from SIMEX. - Sure, Nick.
交易所欠我们七十七亿八千万日圆           好的
Then fax Brenda Granger in London, asking for more funds.
叫伦敦总公司的关连多汇点资金
Say we've had a large margin call on our client positions.
我们有客户要求为他们炒I展
How much?
要多少？
A million.
一百万元
Make it two.
二百万元
- Nick! - Mm?
尼克
Nick, it's the phone.
尼克，找你
- Hello? - I'm not disturbing you, am I?
希望没打扰你
It's 2am.
凌晨两点
Oh, Christ. Sorry, mate. Had no idea.
对不起，我没想到
The old farts are getting nervous. They want you to unwind the position a little.
听我说，上头有点紧张         他们要你减少买卖
That's easier said than done. Don't want to send the wrong signal to the market.
朗，并不容易           我不想令市场误会       另外我们下月
Second, we need another 2 million profit by next month to secure our bonuses.
需要二百万英镑利润保障花红
Two million? Ron, what planet do you live on, mate?
二百万？哪里找这么多钱
One minute you want me to unwind the positions...
一方面要我减少买买，一方面又
Failure is not an option, mate.
我们不能失败，全靠你了
See you at the junket in London in three weeks' time.
三周后在伦敦见面
2 million?
二百万元？他们以为我是谁？
Who do they think I am, George Soros?
We were close to the end of another year and I was deeper in the shit than ever.
到年终了，我越加泥足深陷
Barings wanted me to speak at their annual group conference in London.
霸菱要我在伦敦周年会议上发言
I was their star trader, and they wanted to know the secrets of my success.
我是他们的明星要知我成功秘诀
It didn't bear thinking about.
但我没时间去想
- Is Nan staying with Auntie Karen? - Yeah.
兰会留下陪嘉伦吗
- It's the best place she could be. - Aww, poor thing.
她留在这里最好    真可怜
- Has she been crying? - Mm.
她常常哭吗
Has she?
真的吗
Nick! It's for you.
尼克，找你的，朗伯嘉？
Ron Baker.
Ron! Can't believe you tracked me down already.
朗，你这么快已经找到我
Listen, with this conference you'll be away from the trading floor a long time.
近日发生的一切         令你没在市场出现
I had to come back a week early for this funeral.
我回来参加一项葬礼
- I told you, Lisa's granddad passed away. - I'm sorry about that, mate,...
我说过丽莎的祖父去世了                   对不起
...but I'm fighting for your bonus. You need to keep up those profits.
但我为你争取花红      你要努力为公司赚钱
- I couldn't miss this funeral. - No one's asking you to!
我一定要出席葬礼                 我明白
I'll issue you a pass so you can come in on Sunday and trade through the night.
我会发给你一张通行证            让你周日晚进行交易
You won't miss a thing!
便不会错过机会
Get out the fuckin' way!
给我滚...
If he's working this hard he's going to need his food.
若他辛苦工作，需要吃东西
He wants me to go into the office on Sunday night and trade.
我要周日回公司进行交易
Well... no!
不要
That's completely out of order. Let someone else make the profits!
不可能，叫其他人干吧
She's right, Nick. You're not a machine.
她说得对，你不是机器
It's bonus time. If I don't deliver, then everybody loses out.
很快会分花红不努力便前功尽废
It's not fair, Nick. You carry on at this rate, you're gonna be in a right old state.
这样不公平         再这样拼命工作很快会变化石
It's gonna be your funeral next.
下次是你的葬礼
For as much as it hath pleased almighty God...
因神的慈爱
...of his great mercy to take unto himself...
带领他的灵魂进入天堂
...the soul of our dear brother here departed,...
...we therefore commit his body to the ground.
他的肉身入土为安
Earth to earth, ashes to ashes,...
尘归尘土归土
...dust to dust.
Good to see you, son. Sorry occasion, but there you go.
孩子，见到你真好，对不起
- He had a good innings. - That's the main thing.
临终时很安祥               这足够了
So how's it going over there?
你在那边情况怎样    还可以
- Can't complain. - We're all proud of you.
我们以你为豪    没什么大不了
- What you've achieved. - It's no big deal.
Don't be so bloody modest!
太谦虚了，你是抹灰匠的儿子
You a plasterer's son!
I just wish your mum could have been here to see it.
真希望你妈能见到你的成就
So do I.
我也是
I'll try not to let you all down, Dad.
我不会令你们失望
- What did you say? - It's OK, it's just jet lag.
你说什么    不！只是睡得不好
Don't pay any attention to me.
别在意我的话
I felt sick going into the office,...
我讨厌回公司
...seeing all the people I'd been avoiding for months.
看到多月来我逃避的人
It was one thing to con people over the phone, quite another to do it to their face.
我只和他通电         在他们面前要伪装一切
Nick? That's you, isn't it?
尼克         是你吗
Nick Leeson? I heard you were coming in.
尼克利森，听闻你会来
You haven't the vaguest idea who I am, have you?
你应不知道我是谁
Brenda? Of course.
佩达  当然认识，
- I'm sorry. How are you? - So I finally get to put a face to the voice!
你好吗            终于见面了
- My God, you are so young! - Well, ageing rapidly, I'm afraid.
老天，你这么年轻               但我却很老
Can you come into my office? I really do need to talk to you about the figures.
尼克，到我办公室          我想讨论那些数目
I'm meeting Peter Norris in three minutes.
佩达，三分钟后要见彼得
Oh. Well, do come in right after, OK?
开会后来见我好吗
Nobody out there can answer our questions but you.
只有你能解答我的难题
And they just asked for another ton of funding.
他们要求另一笔贷款
- All right. This one? - Yeah.
好，这个吗？        对    对
Brenda was my cash lifeline.
佩达是我好帮手
She was the last person I wanted asking awkward questions.
But first I had to deal with Peter Norris.
但我要先处理好罗斯
He's such a red-hot trader I'm having him come in overnight!
他是一流经纪  我安排他来这里专负责日经指数
Are you really?
真的吗
You can't keep Nick away from the floor. He's the key man in Singapore.
你不能把尼克调离    他是新加坡市场的灵魂
Sounds like you're the key man in Asia.
听来你是亚洲的人才
He's insane! You should see how he takes that market on.
他是疯癫的  你该看看他的表现
- Are you enjoying yourself? - Yes, it's all right.
尼克，享受这工作吗                    还可以
"All right"?
喜欢？
Now, we need to talk about merging the sales areas in Asia. Nick has some views.
谈谈亚洲的股票买卖吧   尼克有他的观点
If we can replicate his success in Hong Kong and Tokyo...
若把他的方法用在...  香港和日本市场
What do you think, Nick?
尼克，认为怎样
It does make a lot of sense to merge.
这个建议很有道理
There would need to be controls, of course,...
但我们要控制得宜
...but the trading books can be used to supplement a customer's requirements...
我们可以用交易市场的规条...  来满足客户的要求
...and increase information flows.
增加资讯交流
Synergetically.
互助互惠
Exactly. Synergy.
对
So you see, Peter, Nick agrees.
彼得，尼克也同意
And he's been very successful with his customers. They love him!
他的客户对他宠爱有加
Yes, excellent. Well, keep up the good work,...
对...很好，继续努力
...and Ron, you sort out what you want with this merger.
朗，负责今次合并计划
Now, gentlemen, I really have to...
各位，很高兴见面
- Good to meet you. - Nice to meet you. Cheers.
稍后见
I think that went well. He seemed to go for the merger idea.
不错，他同意了合并计划
- Oh, he did. He really went for it! - This'll be good for you too, Nick.
对，他的确同意了  尼克，这样对你很有利
They'll give you some kind of fancy new title!
你会提升
Uh... Nick!
尼克？
Nick!
Ron!
朗？
Being good...
单做好本分是不足
...is not good enough!
Everyone must be connected to our strategy, or we will find you...
每人都要和策略配合
...and weed you out!
否则便被赶离场
Information arbitrage is our business.
内幕消息是重要财路
If you don't know what an information curve is, then find out!
所以必须要有独具慧眼
Position yourself in an information curve.
令自己成为资讯的提供者
Dominate the curve!
控制市场
Nick Leeson, who most of you know and all of you have heard of,...
尼克利森是新加坡最有名的
...runs our operation in Singapore,...
股票经纪
...which I want all of you to try to emulate.
我要你们跟他学习
Now, you'll hear later from Nick about how he does it,...
很快会听到尼克的分享
...but I just want to drive home to you guys...
我想你们记着
...that if you could all think about Nick...
记者尼克所说的话
...and perhaps come up with ideas to follow his footsteps,...
跟随他的脚步
...Barings will become...
霸菱便成为
...one of the most successful operations in the derivatives business.
最成功的商业机构
Oh, fuck!
该死
Oh, we are gonna make so much money!
我们将会赚很多钱
But more to the point,...
但最重要的是你
...you are gonna make...
会赚很多钱
...so...
...much...
会赚很多钱
...money.
Oh, Nick!
尼克
Nick... wake up.
尼克...醒醒    丽莎
- Lisa... - We're meant to be going to the dinner!
去吃晚饭    我不能去
I can't. I can't face it. I can't take it any more.
我不能再面对他们
I'm not going back after Christmas. You can't make me.
圣诞节后我不回去
What?! You're sitting next to Peter Norris in the seat of honour!
你怎么了？ 你很荣幸坐彼得罗斯身旁
Don't tell me you missed your presentation too.
你还要发表演辞
- I've been drinkin'. - I never would have guessed!
我喝了酒    我知道
I think it's downright rude. You can't let everybody down.
他们在等你呢  你不能令他们失望
You don't understand, Lisa.
你不明白
I'm sitting on a fuckin' volcano. I can't go back!
我已泥足深陷，不能回头
And what about your bonus?
你的花红呢
Now, stop babblin' and get yourself dressed!
别赖了，快更衣
I'll give you volcano, Nick Leeson - right up your bum!
利森，你不起来便打你
Lisa... oi!
丽莎
In you go! You stink!
你很臭    丽莎，不要...
Oh, Lisa...
丽莎
You bitch!
你该死
- I'm gonna kill you now! - Look at you! What a disgusting sight!
我要杀了你                看看你多丑怪
Aagh, no, you're gonna get me all wet, Nick!
尼克，把我弄湿了
Nick. You've got to get dressed. Stop.
你要快点更衣
You've got to get dressed!
Promise me you'll always love me, Lisa.
丽莎，答应我永远爱我
That whatever happens, you'll always love me.
不管怎样，也爱我吗
Oh, of course I will!
当然会
You're my man, aren't you?
你是我的男人，不是吗
It was crazy going back. I couldn't hope to survive the end-of-year audit.
我只渴望能平安渡过年终的年结
There was that little matter of the 7.78 billion yen...
我把七十七亿八千万日圆转到
...which I'd fabricated to plug the hole in the five eights account.
我把七十七亿八千万日圆转到  88888户口
I should have told Lisa when I had the chance,...
我应告诉丽莎
...but this voice kept telling me...
但有把声音对我说
...I'd traded out of losses before - I could trade out of them again.
我曾经能渡过难关，今次也得
What's this letter all about?
封信怎么了
Well, it's from SIMEX.
新加坡交易行寄来
Yes, I know it's from SIMEX. It came while you were away.
我知，你不在时寄来的
"It appears that you have financed the trading positions...
贵公司拥有一个88888户口
...held by sub-account 88888. "
以作股票交易买卖
"If this is the case you have violated SIMEX Rule 822,...
若属实，便违犯了
...which bans members from financing the trading margins of their customers. "
期交所822条例 为客户提供财政资助作I展炒卖
They're just banging on about our intra-day funding limits.
他们会找我们麻烦
Well, what is sub-account 88888 anyway?
这个88888户口到底是什么
It's a customer account. We have umpteen trading accounts.
是客户的户口，我去查
I'd have to look into it.
We're the number one trader, and they're tying us up in red tape.
我们是最出色经纪  所以会受到严密监察
Anyone would think they didn't want us to trade.
人人认为他们想阻我们
Er... I'll draft an answer for you.
我会模拟答案
Yeah, do that, will you? Get it on my desk by the morning.
好的     明天早上放在我桌上
Of course, Simon.
好的
Lisa?
丽莎
Lisa, what are you doing?
丽莎，你干什么
I'm bleeding, Nick!
尼克，我流血
Why didn't you tell me?
为何不告诉我
Cos I was waiting till I was sure!
我想先验证...
- You're not angry with me, are you? - Of course I'm not angry, my love.
你不会嬲我吧                  亲爱的，当然不会
- You want the baby, don't you? - I really want the baby.
尼克，你要孩子，对吗
I want lots and lots of babies. All right?
当然，我还要很多孩子呢
Your wife is OK...
你的妻子没事了
I'm afraid she's lost the baby.
但孩子没有了，
I'm sorry.
真可惜
That was the turning point.
那次成为转折点
That was when I decided I couldn't stand around any longer...
我开始不能再承受压力
...hoping the market would move in my favour.
希望市场跟我的意向走
I was gonna have to make it move.
我要令这个实现
I didn't care how much money it took.
花多少钱也不计
I was gonna go for broke.
这人为公司成为全球...
The man is single-handedly generating a fifth of the group's worldwide profits!
第五位赚钱的机构
I know. But $30 million in margin payments? For one day's trading?
我知道... 但一天内动用三千万元支付I展
You don't seem to understand. The volumes are enormous!
不，你不明白，这是小意思
Nick's guy is the biggest player on SIMEX!
尼克是新加坡市场最大的玩家
- Hello? - Nick.
喂    尼克，我是佩达
It's Brenda.
Listen, buddy. This is putting a terrible strain on our borrowing.
我们的财政拍档收紧我们的贷款
Tony Hawes is all over me about your cash calls.
东尼贺斯要查你的现金流量
I hear you. But London is the cash cow for the business here.
是，我正在听   但伦敦和这里不同
We just don't have access to any other funds.
我们没有资金来源
If you keep hassling me I've a good mind to stop trading.
若你再骚扰我   我宁愿停止交易
No, no, Nick. It's OK. Listen...
不要，好吧，没事了...
Just get back to me with some meaningful figures, OK?
那么给我一些数据吧
Fuck off.
滚开
Hello?
喂...
Thank goodness I caught you. I know Brenda's giving you a hard time...
尼克，幸好找到你        我知佩达难为你
I don't think any of you understand how it works out here.
你们不懂这里的运作
You may be right, mate. Anyway, consider it sorted.
你说得对...
But you are gonna have to start reducing these positions.
但你可否减少交易数量
Well, Ron, I'll see what I can do, all right?
朗，我尽力吧，好吗
While I've got you, about your bonus...
还有...有关你的花红
The budget's tight. Though you've been exceptional there's not much to go round.
现时财政紧缩，知你很出色  所以别期望太大
I thought we had a record year!
今年不是赚大钱吗
Yeah. That said, I've put in a special plea to Peter and he's agreed to go up to 350.
对  所以他愿意给三十五万元花红
350? That's ridiculous!
三十五万？真是荒谬
I'm really pushing out the boat for you, mate.
我已经为你尽力争取
I'm busting my balls here. I made us the top house in SIMEX.
我很努力工作
We even got that award for all the business we're doing!
我是市场最出色经纪  还因此得到奖项
Yeah, I know that, Nick.
这点我知
Look, I'll see what I can do.
我尽力吧
I'll see if it can't start with a four, eh?
看我能够争取四十万
That was their opening offer.
He'd have thought something was wrong if I'd accepted it straight away.
若以为我会接受        便错了
Yeah, it's like winning the lottery.
对，像中六合彩嘛
They must think the world of you.
他们应答谢你呢
What's the matter, Lisa?
丽莎，怎么了
What do you think's the bloody matter, Nick?
尼克，你以为什么
Everything's changed!
一切都改变了
I just wanna go home. Get the hell out of here and go home.
我想回家，想离开这里
But... you wanted to come back. What about the bonus?
你想回来，还说为花红
Well, can't you get the bonus in London?
在伦敦拿到花红吗
Please, Nick! I wanna get on with my life.
尼克，我想重头开始
I wanna start a family. I'm going stir-crazy here all on my own!
建立家庭  离开这令人疯癫的地方
Calm down. Look, I just need a bit more time to sort things out, turn things around.
好吧，冷静点，慢慢来...
No! You're up at dawn and then you come back at night and collapse into bed...
你早出晚归，回来时倦极了
How am I meant to get pregnant again if we never make love?
我们不干怎再次怀孕
I know. But this could set us up for life!
我知，会影响我们生活
- When's bonus day? - 24th of February. Just five weeks to go.
何时取得花红？          二月二十四，还有五周
Right, we're gonna leave on the 25th.
好吧，我们二十五号离开
I mean it. I'm calling the furniture removers tomorrow.
我叫搬运公司来收拾
All right.
好吧
With everything else closing in on me, I'd forgotten about the mooning charge.
无论任何事我要熬下去
When it finally came up, I was facing a possible jail sentence.
因为上到法庭我可能要坐牢
The charge has been reduced to a misdemeanour.
控罪减为行为不检
The maximum penalty is a $200 fine. I think we should plead guilty.
最高罚款是二百元        我们应该认罪
Thank you very much.
谢谢你    谢谢
It was uncanny. I'd got away with it again!
真够运，又再逃过大难
To the Singapore legal system, a shining example to the free world!
为新加皮司法干杯       为自由世界干杯
We bared our all for Barings.
为霸菱而喝采
Bearer bonds takes on a whole new meaning after this!
我们的债权人松口气了
Talk about a bear market! Hello? Mooners Anonymous.
你说得对    喂？情况怎样
This is Wei Wei from Coopers & Lybrand. Is that Nick?
高柏来班公司的维维             尼克吗
Speaking.
对
I'm compiling the end-of-year audit. There seems to be a big hole in the accounts.
我核对年结时发现有数目不符
I'm missing the 7.78 billion yen...
新加坡股票市场少点我
...receivable from SIMEX.
七十七亿八千万日圆
Nick, can you hear me?
尼克，你听到吗
Is everything all right?
没事吧
It's a little complicated. What do you need?
情况有点复杂，想怎样？
I can't find any paperwork.
我找不到文件
It was an over-the-counter trade between Speer, Leads and Kellagg...
这是嘉诺和伦敦霸菱的交易
...and Barings London. It fell through the computer system.
所以没记在电脑 我和电脑的经理
I'll have a word with the systems manager.
商讨后再找你
I need three bits of paper.
我要三方面文件
One: confirmation from SLK that the 7.78 billion yen will be paid.
第一是嘉诺证明文件  显示支付那七十七亿八千万
Two: sight of your bank balance to show it's been received.
第二是你们的银行结算  显示接收了
And three: a note from Ron Baker saying he's aware of the deal and approves it.
第三是朗伯嘉的证明信  表示他知这交易
Well?
怎样？
Oh, it's just a computer glitch.
没什么，电脑出错
They're doing their annual audit.
他们进行结算
And so, with scissors and paste, I created $78 million out of thin air.
将会支付七十七亿八千万日圆  利用剪贴便创造了
This was forgery, pure and simple,...
伪造过程非常简单
...and there was no going back.
迫我走到不归路
- Nick! - Simon.
尼克
Jesus, you almost gave me a heart attack!
辛逊，你把我吓倒
- What's this missing seven billion yen? - Oh, that's a nightmare.
为何会损失七十亿日圆                  那是个噩梦...
It's an OTC trade that was incorrectly booked.
上月的结算纪录错误
The auditors are really on my case about it.
核数师因这问题找我
It's a pain in the arse, but we've got to get it sorted.
我们要尽快纠正错误
The point is, we're owed the money by SLK.
问题是欠SLK款项
Who the hell are SLK?
谁是SLK？
Speer, Leads and Kellagg. It's a brokerage house.
是嘉诺股票行
Better send me a memo as soon as. Get these auditors off my back.
给我内部报告            要尽快解决
Sure, Simon. Don't worry, I'm onto it.
当然，放心，我会处理
Bonnie, it's Nick. Listen. Listen very carefully.
邦妮，我是尼克       留心听我说
Transfer 7.78 billion yen from the client account to the house account tomorrow.
从客户中取七十七亿八千万日圆  转到公司的户口内
But it won't go!
但资金不足怎进行交易
There isn't enough money.
I know that, but then you can reverse it. It's just an electronic transaction.
我知，但可以立刻转回去
But I want the transfer done. And I want the bank...
只是电子交易  我需要进行
...to send us a fax of the statement, showing the 7.78 billion yen credit.
要在银行月结上  看到这宗交易
All right, Nick. If you say so.
好的，尼克，就这样办
Cheers, Bonnie.
谢谢你
Nick?
尼克
What's all this about seven billion yen?
那七十亿怎么了？
Someone from London, Tony Hawes, was looking for you.
有个叫东尼的人从伦敦来电找你
Jesus Christ, if I hear any more about this seven billion yen...
我不想再听到这七十亿元的事
It's about $70 million, innit?
这是天文数字
What do you reckon? Red or blue?
怎么了？蓝或红
You think I just walked off with $70 million?
以为我盗取这七十亿
I didn't say that.
我没说
It's a computer error.
是电脑出错
You need someone in the back office, I told you. You're not bloomin' Superman!
需要人协助文职工作   说过你不是超人
Don't start all that again.
丽莎，别吵架
It wouldn't have happened if I'd been there.
若我在可以帮助你
Right. I'm goin' out.
对，我出去
- Where are you going? - To get pissed.
去哪里                       去死
If anyone calls, tell 'em I've gone to South America.
有人找我，说我在南美洲
Well, you can bloody stay there, then!
你别回来好了
Twat!
该死的
What have you done now, Leeson?
利森，干什么
What have you done now?
你到底干了什么
（尼克和丽莎启）
Come in.
进来
I thought you'd like to know the audit's been cleared.
核数工作完成了
- Nick sent the papers. Everyone's happy. - Thanks, Ron.
尼克把文件交了   他们很满意    谢谢
Technically we've breached SIMEX rules, but it was just a non-transaction.
技术上是违反    新加坡市场规例
With any luck...
但基本上没有进行过交易
...the auditors won't mention it, or we may have problems with the local regulator.
希望核数师不会提到这点   否则监察机构会找麻烦
Sounds sensible.
言之有理
Do you know, Nick made $10 million doing arbitrage in a week?
知道尼克一周内赚到一千万吗
That's about... half a billion dollars a year.
一年便有五亿
The guy's a turbo arbitrageur!
他是钞票印刷机
If he's doing that amount of business for that amount of profit,...
以他赚钱的速度
...why don't we shut down the rest of the bank? We're just overhead.
为何不索性把银行关掉了  连运作也省却
Yeah!
对
- Hello? - Nick,...
尼克
...are you avoiding me? I've been trying you for days.
你在逃避我吗？找你多天
Sorry, Tony, it's been chaos.
东尼，对不起，我们忙于核数
The audit went through. I thought you knew.
- It's this SLK thing. - It's all been cleared up.
是SLK的事    已经查清楚
I know. What's bothering me is where you got all the money to actually...
我知道  你如何有钱支付给SLK
...well, pay SLK in the first place.
你如何有钱支付给SLK
I mean, it's the equivalent of $78 million!
总数共七千八百万元呢
It doesn't add up, you know.
这项数目不对
It's obvious. It's part of the funding we've had from you over the past few weeks.
东尼，钱是你数星期批给我们的
Yes.
是    全数我会汇回给你
So, the same figure will flow back to you.
I see. You're saying that some of the funding was used to pay SLK?
我明白  你是说那些钱一向都给SLK吗
That's right, Tony. So we'll be able to pay it back to you.
对，所以我们有能力还款给你
That'll be good. Er... getting our funding down will be good.
很好   请尽快把钱交给我们
I'm having to juggle quite a few balls.
我还要处理其他问题
We all are, Tony. Look, I've got to dash.
我们也是，东尼，信我
I've got company for dinner.
要挂线了，我要参加公司晚宴
Of course. Thanks, Nick.
尼克，谢谢你把事情交待清楚
Thanks for... clearing that up.
Yes, Ron. What do you want?
朗，你想怎样
It's me, you wanker! Danny.
怎么了，我是丹尼
Bubble? What are you doing calling me in the middle of the night?
是“吹波”  这么晚找我有什么事
Are you anywhere near a TV?
你附近有电视吗
I suggest you tune in to CNN.
快看美国有线新闻
The worst damage was in the seaport of Kobe.
神户海港所受的破坏最严重
Road and rail links are shattered...
道路及铁路糟破坏
Jesus, an earthquake! That's all we fuckin' need.
房屋倒塌，多处起火   该死，是地震
This is gonna kill the market, man.
市场一定受到影响
The Nikkei's gonna fall through the fuckin' floor!
日经指数大幅下泻
...milling around in search of help.
Rescue operations are going to be complicated, long...
...and expensive. Mike Chinoy, CNN, reporting live from Tokyo.
Market's down 300 points, you stand there cool as a fuckin' cucumber.
股市下跌三百点，我们有难了
The way I see it, it's an opportunity.
“吹波”  ，我认为是机会
I'm gonna buy into the market. Buy it all the way back up to 19,000.
我要趁低入市  很快股市回升至千九点
Fuckin' true what they say about your gonads, mate.
你的眼光真准
See what I mean?
看到了吧
Think I'll give Fernando a bell in Tokyo, see what's shakin'. No pun intended.
我致东京的法兰度  看情况怎样 应不会摇动
It's Nick. What's the situation in Kobe?
法兰度，神户的情况怎样
We've been trying to contact our friends, but the lines are down.
我们无法联络那里的朋友
Hold it a second. We got movement.
尼克，我们这边有变
Holy shit, selling! There's some selling!
有人大手沽货
Fuckin' hell, it's in free fall!
股市大泻
I've never seen it move so fast.
从没见过市场下跌这么快
350! 350!
三百五十...
350!
Nick?
尼克
Sure you don't want us to stay?
不要我们留下吗
No, I... I'm fine. You go.
不，我没事，回去吧
You'll make it right, Nick.
你会熬过的
We all believe in you.
我们对你有信心
50 million!
五千万
I,...
我...尼克利森
...Nicholas Leeson,...
...have lost...
在一天内损失了五千万英镑
...50 million quid...
...in one day!
在一天内损失了五千万英镑
What does he do, exactly?
他干了什么
That's what no one seems able to explain.
那边无人向我解释
It's simple. He switches contracts between Osaka and SIMEX,...
很简单 将大阪和新加坡市场的合约对调
...exploiting price differentials between the two markets.
看看两个市场的价格差距
That's how he offers the best deals to our customers.
然后用最好的价钱卖给顾客
If it's that easy, why isn't everybody doing it?
这么简单为何没有人这样做
Because he's absolutely in the vortex of the information curve over there.
因他有内幕消息
He's discovered a whole new way of making money.
发现一项全新的赚钱大计
Well, he's giving us horrendous funding problems, that's all I know.
我知我们的基金遇到难题
He doesn't do things by the book, Ron. He just doesn't respect the rules.
他不按规条办事，不遵守规例
Is he really the kind of person we should be employing at Barings?
霸菱银行要聘请这样的人吗
Oh, fuck the rules. It's barrow boys like Nick who are turning the City around.
东尼，别管规条 像尼克这小子才能令伦敦反转
You can't run a modern financial centre with a bunch of Hooray Henries.
但我们不能像他管理现代的财经
Bastard!
混旦
Wakey-wakey!
华基    你仍在买卖吗
- What's the action, mate? - You tell me.
华基    你仍在买卖吗    情况怎样
The market's up and down like a tart's knickers.
天晓得，市场波幅不定
- I think the worst is over. - Who knows? You could be right.
我猜最坏的情况已过了    或许是吧
Well, that's my hunch anyway.
我相信我的想法
Listen, I was out last night with that Loy.
我昨晚和路透社记者莱外出
You know, that journo from Reuters.
He's convinced there's no mystery customer.
他相信你没有神秘顾客了
He reckons it's you. He thinks you're trading on your own account.
他们相信那是你 他猜你在没合约下为自己作买卖
Without the bank's approval.
他猜你在没合约下为自己作买卖
Now, you're not that crazy, are you?
这不是真的吧    你认为呢
What do you think?
Who, then? Beaumarchais? I thought he'd given you the elbow.
若是真的，那班老鬼必定杀了你
- I can't tell you. - Come on. It's me, Danny Boy!
这是秘密  来吧，我是自己人
I could tell you... but I'd have to shoot you afterwards.
我可告诉你，但之后要杀你灭口
I know one thing. If Customer X didn't exist,...
若顾客X不存在，你便要创造他
...you'd have to invent him.
45 million? You've already had 100 this week.
四千五百万？本周已调动一亿
Everybody's had an advance margin call from SIMEX on their client positions.
每位新加坡股市的顾客  接到期指的通知电话
They're worried about stability with these big movements.
他们担心股市波动会影响市场
It's an emergency measure?
这是紧急情况吗    对
Isn't everybody squealing out there?
各人都沽售出货吗
No, we'll get it back when the market calms down.
待市场转好后会再入货
Nick, when are you gonna reduce these positions?
尼克，你会沽货吗
The bean counters are freakin' out!
财经管理公司的会计师很担心
Ron! Didn't know you were there.
朗，我不知你在这里
For fuck's sake, we've had the Bank of International Settlements...
我们的客户问霸菱能够支付
...asking if Barings can meet its margin payments!
I展款项 任何差错都会影响公司形象
- It is not good for the image! - I hear you, Ron. It's a tight market.
朗，市场竞争激烈
Yeah, well, you've really gotta try.
所以要尽力而为
Take a hit on it if you have to.
别让客户损失
I know Norris is gonna want to discuss it with you when he's out there next week.
罗斯下周会和你商讨这个问题
Norris?
罗斯
- I didn't know he was coming. - Yeah, with Tony Hawes.
我不知他来          他和东尼贺斯一起到
They want to check the numbers. Iron out these funding problems once and for all!
他们要核数找出基金的问题
There was no way I could reduce my positions without the market collapsing.
我不能在市场不下泻时削减欠款
By the time they got to Singapore I was in deeper than ever, faxing Brenda daily,...
他们到新加坡时我已泥足深陷
...30, 40 million dollars at a time.
每次亏损三、四千万元
They were gonna kill me.
他们不会放过我
Lookin' like shit, Nick.
你看来糟透了
Lookin' like fuckin' shit, mate.
- Good evening, sir. - Good evening.
晚安    晚安
His approach shot sliced into the woods...
- Nick. There you are. - I'm sorry I'm a little bit late.
尼克，你在这里                对不起，我迟了
- What'll you have? - A beer would be great, thanks.
很高兴见到你              你喝什么？    啤酒
Another Tiger, please.
再来老虎啤
Nick...
尼克
- How was the market today? - It stayed between 18,000 and 18,300.
今天市场怎样            今在一千八百三十之间上落
It's settled after the earthquake.
地震发生后已经稳定下来
Happy with the positions you're running?
你手上的帐户还可以吗
I'm relaxed. They're March contracts, so I'll let them expire.
它们都是主要客户的合约  可以待它们自动终结
- Good. - Thanks.
很好     谢谢
Now, we've had a lot of stick... over funding.
我们有太多投资基金了
Brenda Granger tells me we're borrowing all over Japan to get the funds to you.
班迪说他们向日本公司...       借资金给你
People are beginning to talk, Nick.
市场上开始有谣传了
I understand.
我明白
I understand completely.
我完全明白
Excellent.
很好...
Good man.
很好
And that was it. That was apparently all he had to say on the subject...
这么简单  他看来好像要揭穿我的秘密
...of my enormous exposure causing so many ulcers throughout Barings.
这秘密足以令霸菱银行王国倾倒
Better than you get in London, that's for sure!
比伦敦情况更好
You'll enjoy the next course.
很快送上下一道菜式
- Lobster, sir? - No, thanks. I'm not very hungry.
要龙虾吗             没有，我不太肚饿
I should have been able to relax after that,...
办完事后  我可以好好休息
...but I couldn't stop thinking about the losses in the five eights account.
但我不停在想那个幸运户口
Shame you can't stay for the match on Saturday.
真可惜，你不能欣赏周六的比赛
You're down for 450, aren't you?
你有四百五十万元花红
Your bonus.
你的偿金？只剩下周时间
Only a week to go.
Sorry?
什么？
Have you thought about what you're going to do with it? Only a week to go!
只剩下一周时间给你想
Ahem! Excuse me. I have an announcement to make.
各位，我有要事宣布
I know that some of you are worried about our exposure in the market,...
我明白你们担心近期的炒卖活动
...and you're probably wondering about the identity of our mystery Customer X.
你们也对我们神秘X客户很好奇
Well, the fact is...
事实上...他并不存在
...he doesn't exist.
We are the customer: Barings.
霸菱就那个神秘客户
Look properly at the five eights account -
你仔细看看五个八的户口
...which is not a client account, it's an errors account -
发现那是个错误户口
...and you'll realise it's concealing losses in the region of 200 million.
用来掩饰亚洲区内  二亿英镑的损失
No, I tell a lie. It's more like 230 after today!
我说谎  到今天损失不止这个数
What are you going to do with all that money, Nick?
你怎样用那笔钱
Well, I won't spend it on futures and options!
我不会用来投资期货和期权
- That's very good. - Very good.
很好    很好
I was living from day to day, hoping for a miracle.
我每天都望天打挂  希望奇迹出现
I wasn't running a position any more. The position was running me.
我不能控制市场，但被市场控制
Man, look at the state you're in. You got the bloody shakes!
你看来很疲乏，昨晚玩得很晚吗
- You been on the razz all night? - Nah.
- I'm just getting killed by the market. - Tell me about it!
这个股市差点把我害死               为什么
I've had a shitty week too.
今个星期并不易过
Penguin? You lucky sod!
你搞什么
Do you know how rare they are?
你知他们多疯狂吗
Do you know?
- It ain't that bloody funny! - Lucky Leeson!
我不是开玩笑    你真够运
You have it. I'm not laughing at you, Bubble.
“吹波”  ，我不是取笑你
Fuck! Sorry.
对不起
'Ey-ey-ey-ey-ey! You really are in a bad way, ain't ya?
你的情况真不妙吗
What's the matter?
什么事
I have an unauthorised position.
我干了非法的交易
Fuckin' hell.
该死，数目多大
How big?
Big enough to be a problem.
很棘手    真可怜
Poor bastard!
I can't say it comes as a complete surprise.
不过我早料到，
- Does Lisa know? - No, she'd kill me.
丽莎知吗       不，否则她会杀了我
She's got enough on her plate. She's just waiting for my bonus so we can go home!
真可怜，这对她是双重打击  她望我能取得花红然后回老家
So what are you gonna do?
你打算怎样
Well... I just have to keep buying futures to support the market.
我要继续买期货直至补仓成功
If it sticks at 18,000, my options are still in the money...
若指数维持在一万八千点
I could get the position back.
我有期权在手定会取回控制权
- I may even come out ahead. - Nick...
可能会赚钱
You listen to me now, right.
听我说...别和市场斗气
You don't fight the market, man.
Even if you can make the margin calls, what happens when the contracts expire?
即使你投资I展若合约完结怎办
The way the market's going, your losses could be catastrophic!
到时你更泥足深陷
Five for a thousand, five for a thousand! Come on!
一千放五手...
George, move this fuckin' market! If it stays below 18,000 we're dead!
佐治，快令股市上升 停留一万八千点以下便无法翻身
Nick.
尼克
Nick, I really need to go over some of the figures with you.
东尼         尼克，我要和你核对帐目
Sure, Tony.
可以
Back in a minute.
很快回来
Seven for five! Seven for five!
股市急泻，我无能为力...
I'm sorry. Money!
对不起...
I'd thrown away countless more millions, and it hadn't made a dent.
再损失金钱但始终未能扭转局面
I was only one day from bonus day, but the game was up.
还有一天要发花红  但游戏继续，
I was beaten.
我战败了
Oh, Nick, you're a bloody fool, aren't you?
尼克，你真笨
Well, it's not the end of the world. You've got your health, you've got me...
不是世界末日，你有健康有我
Shame about the bonus.
可惜花红没有了
Sorry.
对不起
Slow down. The video shop's on the next left.
把车慢下来，商铺就在邻近的铺位
- I wanna get our deposit back. - Right.
我要取回按金    好吧
We're gonna need it, darlin'.
我们要这个
- Hello? - The positions have got bigger!
尼克，情况越来越不妙
If they aren't reduced I'm coming out there to sort you out!
若它们还没改善我要对付你
- You're very faint, Ron. - And what's this rumour I hear?
朗，你真不够运
There's a rumour that we're the customer.
听到传言说我们就是那个顾客
Sorry, you're gonna have to speak up.
对不起，你要大声点
Tell me we're not the customer, Nick.
说我们不是那个顾客吧
- I'm losing you, Ron. - Nick! Nick, are you there?
这里接收很差             尼克，你还在吗
Goodbye, Ron.
朗，再见了
They wouldn't give me the full 200, but I stood my ground and got 180.
我坚持要退回按金       他们只发还180元给我
Good girl.
干得好
Nick...!
尼克
（新加坡机场）
Excuse me, sir. There's a phone call for you.
先生，请听电话    现在不能
- Not now. - It's Peter Norris. He said it's urgent.
是彼得罗斯先生，他说有事
Oh. Thank you.
谢谢
Would you excuse me?
失陪
Peter?
彼得？
I'm sorry to drag you away from your dinner party.
对不起，打扰你的派对
I'm afraid I've got some rather bad news.
我有坏消息
By the time the shit hit the proverbial fan in London we'd escaped Singapore...
当事情在伦敦曝光后
...to ponder the future and consider my options.
我们已逃离新加坡
If I had any.
我已别无选择
What's gonna happen, Nick?
尼克，以后怎样
They must have got my fax and closed down all the positions on Friday.
应该收到我的传真在周五时停牌
The market seems to be holding up OK.
市场的反应还支持得住
But you're definitely out of a job?
但你一定会被辞退
It could have been a lot worse, but I still lost them a ton of money.
继续令他们损失金钱就不堪设想
I'm starving! Think they do burgers here?
我很肚饿，你猜他们有汉堡包吗
No! You're not having a burger.
不准吃汉堡包，你的肚腩令我恶心
- That tummy of yours is driving me nuts. - Don't stress me, wench!
不准吃汉堡包，你的肚腩令我恶心                    别取笑我
I'll work it off in the gym.
我会去健身
Better still...
别动...
- Stop it. People are watching. - So? I don't care. Come here, girl.
不要，他们在看呢                        我才不管，过来
Jesus Christ, Lisa!
丽莎
（令银行倒闭股票经纪被通缉）
- Barings has gone bust! - What?!
霸菱银行倒闭了    什么
The Chancellor of the Exchequer is trying to calm fears...
主席加尼克
...sparked by the failure of Barings Bank. In a statement to Parliament...
尽力安抚受今次影响的人士
...he denied reports that the British banking system is about to collapse.
国会发表声明        否认英国银行体系将会倒闭
According to him, Barings' failure is a unique situation,...
他说霸菱银行的情况特殊
...which he blames on the actions of a rogue trader in Singapore.
是因新加坡股票经纪所拖累
Estimates of potential losses range from 800 million to over one billion pounds.
估计损失八亿至超过十亿
There's no way of knowing how markets will react when they reopen on Monday.
现在还不能预计周一开市的反应
As the Bank of England tries to put together a rescue package,...
英国银行会推出挽救计划
...with the Sultan of Brunei rumoured as a buyer, time may be running out...
传闻缅甸的苏丹会出手帮助
...for one of Britain's most venerable financial institutions.
但时间无多  我是美国有线新闻记者
Charles Samson, CNN, London.
查理斯森逊在伦敦报导
Fuck!
妈的
How could you not tell me?
你为什么不告诉我
How could you have kept it hidden for all this time, Nick?
你一直守口如瓶
You must have been through hell!
你一定很难受
You would have marched me straight into Simon Jones's office.
你一定叫我去自首
- Too bloody right! - Then I'd have got fired,...
然后我会被辞退，没有翻身余地
...and I couldn't have made the money back. That's all I was gonna do.
No, but you were gambling.
但你在赌博
That's what you were doing. With other people's money.
这根本就是我们的工作
I didn't want to let everyone down.
我不想令人失望
You, my dad, the girls in the office...
你、我爸爸和公司内的女职员
Even Ron bloody Baker!
还有朗
Do you think they're all gonna hate me now?
他们一定很讨厌我
Well, I don't think you're gonna be Mr Popular!
你当然不再受欢迎了
It could easily have been the other way, you know.
人的命运瞬息转变，只差一点
It so nearly was.
Then I'd be a hero.
便成为英雄
Come here. Come here.
过来
I still love ya. Mm?
我仍爱你
- I love you very much. - I love you too.
我非常爱你    我也是
Shall we see if I can do something about that belly?
为你的肚腩做运动好吗
I see. Yes, I understand.
我明白了
No, of course.
不...当然了
Thank you again for your efforts.
谢谢你的帮忙，
Goodbye.
再见
That was the Sultan of Brunei's office. They have decided not to proceed.
是缅甸苏丹的来电
They believe the risks are too great and the time too short, in view of the need...
他们认为时间仓促风险高
...to have a rescue package ready by the time markets open again in the Far East.
不支持今次行动  他们无法在开市前准备文件
Is there really no one else?
没其他方法吗
We've tried everyone. It's hopeless.
全部都试过了，没希望
I therefore have to inform you that Barings is insolvent...
我要告诉大家，由于霸菱欠债
.,.and will go into immediate liquidation.
将会进行清盘
Peter Barings has gone on TV and said there's been a conspiracy.
彼得霸菱接受电视访问   表示有谣传
They've lost 800 million quid!
指他们损失八亿英镑
I lost nowhere near that. It was more like 300!
我只亏损约三亿镑
But Barings didn't do anything Friday. Now the word's out, the market's crashed.
但霸菱在周五没采取行动  所以消息传开后令股市大跌
Bloody idiots!
该死的
They think you've run off on your yacht.
他们已查过你
- What?! - I know. But listen, mate.
什么
You've got no friends here now, so just get the fuck out of Asia.
你要尽快离开亚洲
Get back to London, Australia, anywhere. Just get out.
回去澳洲或伦敦也好
We're tryin'.
我们在尝试
Oi, Nick... get yourself a good lawyer.
还有，尼克，早点找个律师
- Be lucky. - Cheers, mate.
祝你好运    谢谢
Flight 187 to Hong Kong...
一八七号到香港的航机
...leaving from gate two.
从二号入闸
Fuck!
妈的
There's a manhunt all over Asia. They think we're sailing around in our yacht!
整个亚洲都通缉我 以为我们坐游艇到印度尼西亚
- What bloody yacht? - I know. What about the flights?
什么   真荒谬，航机怎样
- There's one to London. Via Singapore. - That's no good.
有班由新加坡飞回伦敦              不妙
There's a flight to Frankfurt. Via Abu Dhabi.
一班由阿布扎比到法兰克福
Let's take it.
乘坐那班
And Lisa...
丽莎...付现金
Pay cash.
- Newspaper, sir? - No, thank you.
看报章吗    不用了，谢谢
- Ma'am? - Er... no, thanks.
小姐    不用了
Nick, take that thing off.
尼克，把帽除下        我们会飞到三万七千尺上空
There's a guy over there lookin' at me.
有个男人在看我们...
I'm not surprised, with that bloody hat on!
当然，你戴着这顶怪帽...
Talk about conspicuous! You're sticking out like a sore bloody thumb.
你看来怪模怪样
Did you say we stop at Abu Dhabi?
我们在阿布扎比停留吗
- That's where they cut your hands off. - Oh, don't be ridiculous!
那里政府会把盗窃者的手砍下来             别说傻话
They just stone you.
他们用石头掷罪犯
What?
什么
I'm sorry, but you've gotta laugh!
对不起，我只想你笑
Poor old Barings, eh? That's what you get for hiring the wrong sort of person.
可怜的霸菱，对吗           他们误聘人选
That was when it hit me -
在我攻其不备时他们便来
...the enormity of what I'd done.
Whatever happened, I knew things were never gonna be the same again.
无论发生什么已没法走回头路
And I've never felt lonelier in all my life.
我从没感到如此孤寂
I love you, Lisa.
丽莎，不论怎样，我爱你
Whatever happens, I love you.
I love you too.
我也爱你
I've got to get back to London.
我要回伦敦
I couldn't stand being in jail in Singapore. I couldn't stand it if I couldn't see you.
我不能在新加坡服刑             不能不见你
Jesus Christ, it's the police!
是警察
They must know I'm on the flight.
他们知我在这里    不一定
Well... no, not necessarily.
Due to our early arrival, passport control will take place as you leave the plane.
由于航机提早到达   你们离开航机时被检查护照
Please have your documents ready.
请准备好护照
See?
丽莎，我很害怕    坚强点
I'm scared, Lisa!
You be strong, OK?
丽莎，我很害怕    坚强点
Danke.
Pass, bitte.
你好吗
Danke. Thank you.
谢谢
Please show your passport.
请出示护照
Where is your man?
你的丈夫呢
I'm her man.
我就是
250 bid on 100! 250 bid on 100! Come on!
二百五十号放一百
Who wants some of that? 250 bid on 100! 250 bid on 100! Come on!
有谁要货？二百五十号放一百二百五十号放一百 二百五十号放一百
And that's it, more or less. That's the end of my story.
这就是我的故事
Barings was eventually sold to the Dutch bank ING for the princely sum of 1.
霸菱终于被丹麦银行lNG收购
Lisa's got a new life as a flight attendant for Virgin Atlantic.
丽莎后来当上维珍妮亚航空空姐
I hear she's got herself a new fella.
听闻她有新男友
As for me, I fought unsuccessfully against extradition...
而我就被由法兰克福
...from Frankfurt to Singapore on charges of fraud, forgery and breach of trust.
引渡回新加坡 被控行骗，伪造文件及违反信托
I was sentenced to six and a half years in prison.
被判入狱六年半
Despite rumours of secret bank accounts and hidden millions,...
虽然谣传指我有秘密户口
...I did not profit personally from my unlawful trading.
但我没有在非法交易中取得分文
To be absolutely honest,...
坦白说我真希望我有这样做
...sometimes I wish I had.
尼克利森在狱中被证实患上癌症
因此在服刑四年半后获假释
丽莎与尼克离婚后改嫁
丈夫在伦敦市一间投资银行工作
~~  I've got something to say
~~  We...
~~  have come a long way
~~  After all the things that
~~  We have been through
~~  I'm glad still to have you
~~  I know you're hurtin'
~~  And though you're hurtin'
~~  It will get better every day
~~  I love all that you are
~~  You are what I live for
~~  After all the things that
~~  That we have been through
~~  I'm...
~~  glad still to have you
~~  I know you're hurtin'
~~  And though you're hurtin'
~~  It will get better every day